#### Contact

domahidizoltan@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ domahidizoltan (LinkedIn) domahidizoltan.github.io (Personal) github.com/domahidizoltan (Other) profile.codersrank.io/user/ domahidizoltan (Other)

### Top Skills

Java Microservices Spring

### Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hungarian (Native or Bilingual)
Romanian (Limited Working)
German (Elementary)

#### Certifications

Presentor in Hello Kotlin Event Triplebyte Certified

# Zoltan Domahidi

Senior Backend Software Engineer | Go Developer | Cloud & Microservices

Budapest Metropolitan Area

# Summary

I'm an experienced software engineer with 15+ years of backend development, 10+ years of distributed systems and 3+ years of Golang development experience. I help companies to build highly scalable cloud applications, being involved in the full lifecycle of the product. I have a focus on quality and knowledge sharing, while I also care about my professional growth. I'm mainly interested in distributed architectures, cloud, and Golang stacks. I'm a constant learner who loves to discover new technologies. In my spare time I learn about Rust and Blockchain application development on Ethereum.

Dear recruiters, at the moment I'm not looking for new positions (otherwise I would answer your job offer emails within 2 working days).

# Experience

Raiffeisen Bank International AG Senior Backend Software Engineer / Golang Developer February 2024 - Present (6 months)

- design and development of the Group of Connected Customers (read)
   service. I took the major part of designing this new service what was simple enough to move fast with the implementation, but also complex enough to have some safety mechanisms and be able to handle bigger load than expected.
- feature development and maintenance of the Customer Master Data Management system
- taking part in technical discussions and helping in system design decisions
- tech stack: Go / Golang, Postgres, Gin, Ginkgo, Neo4j graph database, event sourcing, CQRS, DataDog, Java

CIRCL Technologies Ltd
Senior Backend Software Engineer / Golang Developer
Page 1 of 4

January 2023 - January 2024 (1 year 1 month)

- development and improvement of Proto Energy SaaS product (mostly on payment and sales orders related features)
- building the WebSocket API for the event sourcing (and CQRS) based backend
- writing and maintaining end-to-end tests
- creating the basics of the backend observability with the help of the DevOps team
- proposing code design improvements
- tech stack: Go / Golang, Postgres, Redis, RabbitMQ, WebSocket, AWS
   Lambda, AWS, Docker, Cucumber.js, TypeScript, Github, Grafana, Terraform

#### Alpaca

Senior Backend Software Engineer / Golang Developer July 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 7 months) Budapest, Hungary

- development and improvement of Alpaca's brokerage system; extracting some parts from the monolith application to new microservices
- scale the monthly statement generation and increase the job throughput by ~20x
- build the scalable backend for mobile app push notifications
- working on subscription management and payment related features
- tech stack: Microservices, Go / Golang, Postgres, RabbitMQ, gRPC, Testify, Iris, Kubernetes, Helm, Ansible, Google Cloud Platform, Github

#### Telekom HU

Senior Backend Software Engineer / Kotlin Developer April 2019 - June 2021 (2 years 3 months)

Budapest, Hungary

- development of Telekom's Product Inventory system
- development of Community Engine which provides discounts for committed
   Telekom customers
- messaging, data auditing, testing, and CI related improvements
- supporting the team in technical design and decisions
- giving a presentation about Kotlin
- tech stack: Microservices, Kotlin, Spring Boot 2 (Webflux), Reactor, MongoDB, Kafka, MockK, Junit 5, JPA, RabbitMQ, TestContainers, Spring Cloud Stream (both RabbitMQ and Kafka), Kubernetes, Helm, Gradle, Git, GitLab

Grape Solutions Plc.

Senior Java Software Engineer / Technical Team Lead September 2018 - April 2019 (8 months)

Budapest

- development of Emobility, Hungary's electric car charging IoT platform
- making software architecture and technology decisions
- improving local development environment, code quality, and testability
- mentoring Java developers; giving presentations about TDD & Http-Mocking
- tech stack: Microservices, Java 11, Spring Boot 2 (Webflux), Reactor,

Python, Junit5, JPA, Jooq, Wiremock, Testcontainers, GCP, Docker,

Kubernetes, Istio, Gradle, Git

#### Secret Sauce Partners

Senior Java Developer

April 2018 - September 2018 (6 months)

Budapest

- development and maintenance of Style-Finder, an apparel recommendation system
- tech stack: Java8, Dropwizard, Guice, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Python, Avro, Maven, Git, Circle CI, JUnit 5, TDD, CleanCode

#### **Evosoft Hungary Kft**

Senior Java Developer

November 2014 - April 2018 (3 years 6 months)

Hungary, Budapest

- design and development of a cloud-based Industry 4.0 project for MindSphere, Siemens (stream processing)
- supporting Java technical interviews
- in-house presentations about Clean Code, TDD, Spring Integration, Spring XD, Redis, and ScalaJS
- tech stack: Microservices, Java 8, Spring Boot, JPA, Rest, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Redis, Spring Cloud (Netflix OSS), Spring DataFlow (+ Cloud Stream), Reactor, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Gradle, Git, GitLab CI, TDD, CleanCode, Swagger, RestDocs, JUnit, Mockito, CDC (Pact), BDD (Cucumber)

#### **EPAM Systems**

Java Developer

August 2012 - November 2014 (2 years 4 months)

Budapest, Hungary

- development of a banking application for the Swiss UBS bank
- tech stack: Java7, Spring MVC, JPA, SOAP, JUnit, Maven, SVN, Jenkins, TestNG, JAX-WS, JAXB, Mockito, JMS, Apache Camel

# CIT System Java Developer October 2011 - July 2012 (10 months)

Budapest, Hungary

- development of web applications and Groupon-like pages
- tech stack: Java6, Jsp, MySQL, JavaScript, Android SDK, SVN

## Russmedia Tech PHP Developer May 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 4 months) Oradea, Romania

- development and optimization of high-traffic online magazines
- tech stack: Codelgniter (PHP), MySQL, JQuery, SVN

# Emerigos PHP Developer July 2005 - April 2010 (4 years 10 months) Oradea, Romania

- development of small- and mid-size webpages and webshops
- tech stack: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, CSS, xHTML, Flash AS3/AS2

### Education

Universitatea din Oradea

Engineer's degree, Computer Science (2003 - 2008)

Ady Endre High school, Oradea, Romania Mathematics and Computer Science · (1999 - 2003)